As well as creating Word documents from
scratch, there may be occasions where
you wish to use a preformatted template.
This could be for a CV, poster, flyer,
newsletter, or even a letter template.
To access the templates, you would simply
need to go to the File menu, click on
File and then select New from Template.
Once you've clicked on that, it
will open up the template box.
This will allow you to select
from a wide range of templates.
And as you can see a blank document
is still a template because it
has preformatting applied such
as the font, the font size, the
borders, margins, et cetera.
Other templates available, as you
can see are notes, there's calendar
templates, there's cover letters, there
are CVs, there's journals, newsletters,
brochures and leaflet templates.
So once you've selected the
template that you wish to use, you
would simply double click on that.
And then that will open up in Word.
And once the document is open in
Word, you would then be able to add
your title and then change the text.
As you can see, the text
is already in there.
So it just allows you to go in,
click on each section and then you
could change the text within there.
The thing to remember with templates is
it will automatically apply the formatting
in that section that is already on there.
So in this section, the title.
The title is Times New Roman, 39
so whatever you type in there.
It will automatically apply the
Times New Roman new room, 39 and
other various formatting options
will automatically be applied.
So that's always something to
remember that if you want to use
a template, it can be difficult to
make changes to the template if it
isn't suitable for your purpose.